FORREST MILLS

Dallas, TX

Phone: 830-928-6232 | Email: mills_forrest@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/forrest-mills-dev | GitHub: https://github.com/fmills89 | Portfolio: https://fmills89.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with experience in agile environments and the ability to create capable, reliable, and mobile-first applications. Understand processes and assisted in both front and back-end development for collective effort projects. Aim to problem-solve and work as a team to achieve goals effectively.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS

Libraries: React.js & React Native, Mongoose.js, jQuery

Frameworks: TailwindCSS, Bulma, Bootstrap, Express.js. Jest.js

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL

Misc: Node.js, Rest APIs, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Relational Mapping,

Model-View-Controller, Progressive Web Applications, MERN Stack **Applications:** npm, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas, Github, GraphQL

PROJECTS

Groceries-Helper | https://github.com/fmills89/mobile-grocery-list | https://apps.apple.com/us/app/groceries-helper/id6443589510

- Created with React Native and Expo, Groceries-Helper was created to help assist me on my grocery trips.
- Application is deployed and downloadable via the Apple Store.
- Ongoing development with new features and redesign in progress.

Weather-App | https://github.com/fmills89/weather-app

I https://main--heroic-cactus-a367a9.netlify.app/

- Weather-App was initially a project created during my bootcamp. Covering DOM manipulation, API calls, and local storage utilization.
- Recently I injected TailwindCSS to complete a overhaul of the website. Highlighting mobile and website responsiveness.
- HTML, TailwindCSS, JavaScript

Brew-Me | https://github.com/fmills89/brew-me

l https://fmills89.github.io/brew-me/

- Through group collaboration, Brew-Me is a website where you can search for local breweries.
- Provided implementation of Mapbox API and integrated it with the Brewery API to locate breweries based on user input.
- Tailwind CSS, Javascript, HTML, Mapbox API, Brewery API

EXPERIENCE

2016 - 2021**RSC Rep IV**

Charter Communications

San Antonio, TX

- Coordinated and managed quota moves to meet service level agreements.
- Formulated quota reports, move reports, and forecasted connect activity based on demand, special projects, and marketing forecasts.
- Managed field operations scheduling and workforce management.
- Managed the creation and maintenance of technical skill sets.

Dispatcher V 2015 - 2016

Charter Communications

San Antonio, TX

- Managed and dispatched teams of technicians and ensured timeframes were met. Moved work between teams of technicians.
- Provided technical support via phone for all residential services.
- Processed, scheduled, and corrected work orders.

Technical Support Rep II 2014 - 2015

Charter Communications

San Antonio, TX

- Provided customer care and technical support for all residential services.
- Managed de-escalation of customer escalations.

Technical Support Rep II 2014 - 2014

Volt

San Antonio, TX

- Provided customer care & technical support for all residential services.
- Diagnosed chronic issues, created escalation tickets, and followed up on final resolutions.

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, TX A 24-week intensive program focused on developing technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MERN, MVC Model, OOP, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

A.S. of Science: Northeast Lakeview College, San Antonio, TX 2018 - 2023

CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy: React Native - The Practical Guide [2022]

Credential ID: UC-29293ad0-8938-42d4-b3af-a3ec941a4624

Credential URL: ude.my/UC-29293ad0-8938-42d4-b3af-a3ec941a4624

JavaScript Unit Testing - The Practical Guide

Credential ID: UC-9293f78d-a283-461a-a18e-a375e95da954

Credential URL: ude.my/UC-9293f78d-a283-461a-a18e-a375e95da954